Imagine yourself as a marketing manager at Parch and Posey.
假设你自己是 Parch &amp; Posey 的市场经理
You want to compare Facebook as a marketing channel against all other channels.
你想把 Facebook 与其它市场渠道进行对比
You know Facebook is a great channel for your business but,
你知道 Facebook 是你业务的最重要渠道 但是
is it better than all the rest combined?
它是否大过所有其它渠道的总和？
Let's find out. In order to do this,
我们得找出答案 为此
you'll need to create a derived column.
你得创建一个派生 (Derive) 列
That means you'll take data from existing columns and modify it.
也就是说你从当前列中提取数据 然后进行修改
In previous lessons, we did this using arithmetic.
在前面的课程中 我们使用算术来完成
For this application, we use
在这里 我们使用 CASE 语句
the "CASE" statement which is sequel's way of handling "IF" "then" logic.
这是 SQL 处理 IF - THEN 逻辑的方式
The case statement is followed by at least one pair of "WHEN" and "THEN" statements.
CASE 语句会附有至少一对 WHEN - THEN 语句
Sequel's equivalent of "IF" "THEN".
在 SQL 中 这两者等同于 IF - THEN
It must finish with the word "END".
完成时必须有 END 一词
the conditional statement "channel equals Facebook" is true.
条件语句 channel = 'facebook' 是否为真
If so, it results in the value "yes" being printed in the column "is_Facebook".
如果是真 其结果 yes 就出现在 is_facebook 列中
If not, that Rose value in the is_Facebook column is left "no".
如果不是 在 is_facebook 列中会出现 no
This query makes it pretty easy to see what's happening because we've
用这个查询能轻松查看当前情况
included the case statement along with the channel column itself.
因为它同时包含了 CASE 语句及 channel 列自身
You can check each row to see whether channel
你可以检查每一行以确认 channel 是否
meets the condition "channel equals Facebook",
满足条件 channel = 'facebook'
and then see the result in the column generated using the case statement.
然后查看由 CASE 语句生成的列中的结果
Now, what we'd really like this query to do is fill in those nulls with the word "no".
现在 我们希望能在这个查询中的空值处填入 no
We can do this with the L statement which provides a way to capture values
我们可以用 ELSE 语句 该语句可以捕捉
not specified in "WHEN" "THEN" statements.
WHEN - THEN 语句中没有的值
If we want this new column to keep track of not just our
如果我们想让新列不仅持续追踪我们的
Facebook channel but also the direct channel,
Facebook 渠道 还追踪 direct 渠道
we could change our case statement to use the "OR" operator.
我们可以修改我们的 CASE 语句 用 OR 运算符
a logical condition similar to what you would put in a "WHERE" clause.
你想在 WHERE 子句中放入的逻辑条件
So you can use "END like END" or any other operators you've already seen.
因此你可以用 AND、LIKE、IN 或者其他任何你已见过的逻辑运算符
Imagine yourself in operations at Parch and Posey.
假设你负责 Parch &amp; Posey 的运营
You'd like to classify orders into general groups based on
你想根据订单大小将订单进行分组
order size to get even more granular about inventory planning.
以得到更精细的库存规划
You can use a case statement to define a number of
你可以用 CASE 语句定义多个输出
outcomes by including as many "WHEN" "THEN" statements as you'd like.
通过使用多个 WHEN - THEN 语句
will get evaluated in the order that they're written.
将会对所写的订单进行评估
So, if the value in the total column of a given row is 600,
如果某一行 total 列中的值是 600
it will produce a result of over 500.
将会得出一个超过 500 的结果
If the value in the total column is 169,
如果 total 列的值是 169
the database will first check to see if the total is
数据库会先检查 total 是否大于 500
greater than 500 because that's the first "WHEN" statement.
因为这是第一个 WHEN 语句
169 is not greater than 500,
169 并不大于 500
so we'll move on to evaluate the next "WHEN.
因此我们接着评估下一个 WHEN
This process continues until a logical "WHEN" statement evaluates to
直到逻辑 WHEN 语句评估结果为真
true in which case the "THEN" statement will be recorded in the total group column.
其对应的 THEN 语句将会记录到 total_group 列
For 169, this would happen when the "WHEN" statement results in 101 to 300.
对于 169 当 WHEN 语句的结果为 101 - 103 之间时才会结束
While the above works, it's really best to create "WHEN" statements that don't overlap.
在以上工作中 最好就是构建不重叠的 WHEN 语句
The conditional statement "when total is greater than 500" overlaps with the statement
条件语句 "total &gt; 500"
"when total is greater than 300" for
与 "total &gt; 300" 重叠
every value greater than 500 which is a little confusing.
对每个大于 500 的值 就会有些混淆
A better way to write the above would be to
更好的方法是
define specific groups that don't overlap with one another.
定义不会与其它组重叠的特殊组
You can do this by stringing together multiple conditional statements
为此 你可以将多种条件语句串联起来
with "END" and "OR" the same way you might in a "WHERE" clause.
用 AND 和 OR 与你在 WHERE 子句中串联的方式相同
we'll take these casements just one step further by
我们将要更进一步
combining them with aggregations that we looked at earlier.
将其与之前学习的聚合结合起来